Before we jump into the data analysis process,
قبل الانتقال إلى عملية تحليل البيانات،
let's talk about some of the kinds of problems you might solve as a data analyst.
لنتكلم عن بعض أنواع المشكلات التي قد تتوصلون إلى حل لها بصفتكم محللين بيانات.
When many people hear the term data analyst,
عندما يسمع العديد من الأشخاص مصطلح محلل البيانات،
they picture someone who works at a tech company and probably in Silicon Valley.
فإنهم يصورون شخصًا يعمل في شركة تكنولوجيا وربما في Silicon Valley.
Many data analysts do in fact work at tech companies.
في الواقع يعمل العديد من محللي البيانات في شركات تكنولوجيا.
For example, Netflix uses data analysis to
على سبيل المثال، يستخدم Netflix تحليل البيانات
provide personalized movie recommendations for its users.
لتقديم اقتراحات مخصصة للأفلام لمستخدميه.
Facebook uses it in its news feed ranking algorithm.
يستخدمه Facebook في خوارزمية ترتيب موجز الأخبار.
And OkCupid uses it to predict which people are likely to be good romantic matches.
ويستخدمه OkCupid للتنبؤ بالأشخاص الذين يحتمل وجود صفات متشابهة جيدة بينهم.
In addition to building these kinds of systems,
بالإضافة إلى إنشاء هذه الأنواع من الأنظمة،
many companies also use data analysis to
تستخدم العديد من الشركات أيضًا تحليل البيانات
publish papers or write blog posts about their findings.
لنشر المقالات أو كتابة منشورات المدونة حول النتائج التي توصلوا إليها.
For example, Facebook has studied the ideological diversity of people's political posts.
على سبيل المثال، لقد درس Facebook التنوع الأيديولوجي للمنشورات السياسية للأشخاص.
They found that when posts appear on
ووجدوا أنه عندما تظهر منشورات في
people's news feed written from a different perspective,
ملخص أخبار الأشخاص وتكون مكتوبة من منظور مختلف،
users are less likely to click on those posts.
يكون احتمال نقر المستخدمين على هذه المنشورات أقل.
OkCupid wrote a blog post about
كتب OkCupid منشورًا على المدونة حول
what are the best questions to ask someone on a first date.
أفضل الأسئلة التي يجب طرحها على شخص ما في أول موعد معه.
Did you know that long term couples are very likely
هل تعلمون أنه من المرجح جدًا أن يتفق الزوجان على المدى الطويل
to agree about whether they like horror movies?
حول ما إذا كانا يحبان أفلام الرعب أم لا؟
Data analysts don't just work at tech companies though.
ومع ذلك، لا يعمل محللو البيانات في شركات التكنولوجيا فقط.
Wal-Mart looks through their purchase records and people's posts on
تتطلع Wal-Mart على سجلات مشترياتها ومنشورات الأشخاص
social media in order to figure out what to stock in their stores.
على وسائل التواصل الاجتماعي من أجل معرفة ما يتم تخزينه في متاجرها.
Apparently, Strawberry Pop-Tarts are more likely to sell right before a hurricane.
كما يبدو أن Strawberry Pop-Tarts أكثر عرضة للبيع قبل الإعصار.
Bill James is famous for applying data analysis to baseball.
يشتهر بيل جيمس باستخدام تحليل البيانات على لعبة البيسبول.
He used it to understand who the top performers
لقد استخدمها لفهم من هم أصحاب أفضل أداء
are and how to best predict future performance.
وكيفية التنبؤ بالأداء المستقبلي بشكل أفضل.
And pharmaceutical companies have started to use machine learning to
وبدأت شركات المستحضرات الصيدلانية في استخدام التعلم الآلي
predict which chemical compounds are most likely to make effective drugs.
للتنبؤ بالمركبات الكيميائية التي من المرجح أن تنتج عقاقير فعالة.
Using this, they can make better decisions about which compounds are
باستخدام ذلك، يمكنها اتخاذ قرارات أفضل حول المركبات
likely to be a good use of the resources involved in running a clinical trial.
التي من المرجح أن تحقق أقصى استفادة من الموارد المستخدمة ف التجربة السريرية.
If you'd like to learn more about any of these applications,
إذا أردتم تعلم المزيد عن أي من هذه الاستخدامات،
check out the links in the instructor notes.
تحققوا من الروابط الموجودة في ملاحظات المعلم.